Hello. So, you've learned a lot about CNNs.
你已经学了很多 CNN 知识
And in this lesson, I want to talk about a detail that's been happening behind
在这节课 我将详细介绍
the scenes when we build and train neural networks in PyTorch,
在 PyTorch 中构建和训练神经网络时在后台发生的情况
and that's weight initialization.
也就是权重初始化
Weight initialization happens right when a model is created,
权重初始化发生在模型创建时
before it sees any training data,
并发生在模型看到任何训练数据之前
and it generally only happens one time when a model is first created.
通常只在模型第一次创建时初始化
Weight initialization is all about how you can instantiate a model, like a CNN,
模型初始化是指实例化 CNN 等模型的方式
so that its weights, the model parameters,
能使模型权重（参数）针对给定任务
are starting off with the best initial values for a given task.
设成最佳初始值
You might think of it this way,
可以这么理解
any neuron in a model has some weights and biases that operate
模型中的任何神经元都具有权重和偏差
on some input values and transform them into desired outputs.
这些权重和偏差会对输入值执行运算并转换为期望的输出
It's how you might transform an input image into some class course.
这是将输入图像转换为类别分数的方式
A model is trying to learn the best weights to map inputs to outputs and,
模型将尝试学习将输入映射到输出的最佳权重
say, most accurately classify some given images.
即最准确地分类给定图像
When we did transfer learning,
在进行迁移学习时
we basically initialized a network with the best pre-trained weights,
我们已知某些权重对图像分类来说是最佳值
weights that we know are good values for image classification.
然后 我们会使用这些最佳预训练权重来初始化网络
But for a non-pretrained model,
但是对于非预训练网络来说
how should we initialize the weights?
该如何初始化权重？
We could start for example by saying all the weights are going to be zero,
我们可以首先将权重都初始化为 0
and we'll train them until they're shifted up or down,
然后训练权重并上下调整它们
or we could start out with large weight values,
或者可以初始化为很大的权重值
or even some random values,
甚至使用随机值
and see what happens.
看看会发生什么
These are the questions that we'll be exploring in this notebook.
我们将在这个 notebook 中探讨这些问题
Now, in this notebook, I'm going to demonstrate
现在我将在此 notebook 中演示
the effect of different weight initialization strategies.
不同权重初始化策略的效果
We'll discuss how you might decide on initial weights
我们将讨论如何决定初始权重
and what indicates good initial behavior during training.
以及在训练过程中 什么样的初始行为是好的行为
As usual, this code will be provided for you in our public GitHub repo,
像往常一样 我们将在 GitHub 代码库中公开提供这些代码
so you can work through it too and see how all this works.
因此你也可以自己修改代码
The plan is this,
看看结果如何
we want to define one kind of model, a simple MLP,
我们想要定义一种模型 一个简单的 MLP
and we'll initialize the weights of this model with different values,
我们将用不同的值初始化模型的权重
and compare how the training losses decrease over the first epic or two of training.
并比较在 1-2 个训练周期之后训练损失的降低情况
So, same models, different initial weights.
即 用不同的权重初始化相同模型
Here's an example where we plotted the training loss over
我们在此图中绘制出了
100 batches for two different initialization methods.
两个不同初始化方法在 100 批数据上的训练损失
These are just examples.
这只是两个例子
Some initialization strategies may offer
某些初始化策略
some really big improvements to how the loss decreases,
可能对降低损失改进很大
and others may offer small improvements,
其他策略可能对损失改进不大
such as here, it's very hard to tell the difference.
例如在此图中 很难判断区别
But, big or small, we can learn from all of these differences.
但是无论影响大还是小 我们都能从这些差别中汲取经验
So, what we're going to do is define a simple MLP for
因此我们将定义一个简单的 MLP
classifying images in the Fashion-MNIST dataset.
用于分类 Fashion-MNIST 数据集中的图像
In the first couple cells, I'm going to load in this data with a batch size of 100.
在前几个单元格中 我将加载数据 批次大小为 100
The images in the Fashion-MNIST dataset fall into one of 10 classes.
Fashion-MNIST 数据集中的图像分成 10 个类别
You have T-Shirts, shirts,
包括 T恤 衬衫
sneakers, bags, ankle boots, and so on.
运动鞋 包 短靴等
And here's what a few of those images look like with their respective labels.
这是其中一些图像样本以及相应的标签
You may have seen this before, it's
你可能之前已经见过此数据集
just a dataset of grey scale images of clothing types,
它只是一个服饰类型灰阶图像数据集
very similar to the MNIST dataset.
与 MNIST 数据集很相似
But this classification task is a little more challenging than just 100 in digits.
但是这个分类任务比分类数字图像要难些
A simple dataset like this one is often used to test network performance,
像这样的简单数据集经常用于测试网络性能
because the dataset is simple to use
因为这样的数据集使用便捷
and it's training behavior is fairly well understood.
而且训练行为易于理解
We know for example that we should be able to get the training loss to reliably decrease.
例如 我们能肯定训练损失会稳步降低
So, I load in and look at my data as usual then we get to the model definition,
照常加载和查看数据 然后定义模型
and here's a little diagram of the MLP am planning to build.
这是我打算构建的 MLP 的结构图
This MLP has an input layer,
这个 MLP 有一个输入层
two hidden layers whose size I've specified,
两个隐藏层 大小已指定
and a final output layer,
以及一个最后输出层
the outputs 10 class scores for a 10 clothing types.
输出是 10 个类别分数 对应 10 种服饰类型
The hidden layers will have 256 and 128 nodes respectively.
隐藏层将分别有 256 和 128 个节点
Again, we just want to keep it simple,
我们不想做得太复杂
so that we can focus on how
因为侧重点是了解
weight Initialization affects the performance of such a model.
权重初始化对此类模型性能的影响
If you scroll down a bit, you can see how I've defined that model here.
下拉 就能看见我在这里是如何定义该模型的
I have a flattened input x that I pass to a fully connected layer,
我拉平了输入 x 并传入全连接层
and I apply a radio activation function to each of my hidden layers.
向每个隐藏层应用 ReLu 激活函数
I add some dropout in between,
在中间添加丢弃层
and I have my final fully-connected layer,
这是最终的全连接层
which produces 10 class scores.
它会生成 10 个类别分数
Then to actually train this model,
然后实际训练该模型
I have put that code in a helpers.py file,
我将代码放入了 helpers.py 文件中
which you can find by clicking on this Jupyter icon here.
你可以通过点击这个 Jupyter 图标找到该文件
The purpose of this notebook is not to train the model
此 notebook 的目的
until it performs well on the classification task,
不是训练模型让它在分类任务上表现不错
but rather we just want to see how well the models train given different initial weights.
而是看看如果给定不同的初始权重 模型效果如何
So, let's see what's in the helpers.py file.
我们打开 helpers.py 文件看看
Here's our main helper function get_loss_acc,
这是主辅助函数 get_loss_acc
which takes in a model,
它的输入参数是 model
and the training and validation model.
train_loader 和 validation_loader
In here, I've defined the length of time to train a model choosing two epochs,
在这里定义模型的训练时间 设为两个周期
and I have also defined a loss and optimization function in here.
并且在这里定义了损失和优化函数
I'm using cross-entropy and an Adam optimizer,
使用交叉熵损失和 Adam 优化器
which is one of my gotos,
这是我的做法
but feel free to change this to stochastic gradient descent and see how it performs.
你也可以改成随机梯度下降法 看看效果如何
Then in this function, I'm actually going to train this model for two epochs,
然后在此函数里训练模型两轮
and record the training loss as I go.
并记录训练损失
This loss is going to be recorded in a list called loss_batch.
我将在 loss_batch 列表中记录损失
After a model has trained for two epochs,
模型训练两轮后
I then see how it performs on our validation data set.
看看它在验证集上的效果
I compare the predicted and the correct class,
比较预测类别和正确类别
and see which ones match.
看看哪些类别匹配
Finally, I return the list of training loss over time and that validation accuracy.
最后返回训练损失列表和验证准确率
Then you'll see another helper function compare and it weights,
这是另一个辅助函数 叫做 compare_init_weights
which takes in a list of models.
它的输入是模型列表
For each model in our list,
对于列表中的每个模型
it will record the training loss and the validation accuracy over two epochs,
它将记录两轮的训练损失和验证准确率
and there's some code to visualize this loss and compare at least two models.
然后是可视化损失并至少比较两个模型的代码
Okay. So, you can take a look at
你可以查看辅助函数代码
the helper code and understand how all these things work,
并理解所有代码的工作原理
but there's no need to change anything about the code that I've shown you so far.
但是没必要更改我介绍的这些代码
Now, that I've introduced you to these resources and this notebook,
我已经介绍了这些资源和此 notebook
in the next few videos,
在下面的几个视频中
I'm going to demonstrate how to set your weights appropriately and compare that behavior.
我将演示如何正确地设置权重并比较它们的行为